Hi, my name is John Williams. I'm a Professor of Information Engineering at MIT.
I teach two courses, one in engineering computation and data science,
and the other in architecting and engineering software systems.
And it's been a real pleasure to collaborate with Boeing on developing these courses.
For many years I was Director of the MIT Auto ID Lab where the Internet of Things was invented.
We thought at that time our problem was a hardware problem.
We had RFID chips that we tried to read and the distance that we can read them wasn't that great.
But it turned out our problem really was how to build a system to move that data and make it visible around the world.
So Eric Schmidt says that since the beginning of time until 2003 there was only 5 exabytes of data created.
Today we create that data in just a few hours.
So the problem is how to change that data into business value.
And in these courses we're covering all the stages that you'll be going through.
We're going to leverage the tools and the techniques from web computing through the cloud to AI and machine learning.
And by leveraging these we think that today we can build sophisticated systems that can handle real-time data that give us real business value.
So we think you're going to learn a lot in these courses and I'll be seeing you online. Bye for now.